<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Autumn 2025 on Czech and Slovak Students in Zurich</title>
        <link>https://cssz.ch/semesters/2025-autumn/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Autumn 2025 on Czech and Slovak Students in Zurich</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cssz.ch/semesters/2025-autumn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Sightseeing trip to Ticino</title>
        <link>https://cssz.ch/events/ticino-trip/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cssz.ch/events/ticino-trip/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://cssz.ch/images/events/2025-10-04-ticino-trip/lake_city.jpg" alt="Featured image of post Sightseeing trip to Ticino" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us in exploring the beauty of Ticino, where picturesque lakeside towns meet colourful architecture and Mediterranean flair, and experience the unique blend of Swiss precision and Italian atmosphere. We will start with a walk through the old town of Lugano, followed by a boat ride on the lake. In the lakeside park we will have pizza for lunch and enjoy some ice cream, and those interested will also have the chance to swim in the lake. Then we will decide whether to stay longer in Lugano or continue to Bellinzona, where one can admire the medieval castles listed as a UNESCO World Heritage Site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;connections&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connections:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will take a direct train from Zurich HB at 7:05, arriving at 8:58. &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.sbb.ch/de?stops=[%7b%22value%22:%228503000%22,%22type%22:%22ID%22,%22label%22:%22Z%C3%BCrich&amp;#43;HB%22%7d,%7b%22value%22:%228505300%22,%22type%22:%22ID%22,%22label%22:%22Lugano%22%7d]&amp;amp;date=%222025-10-04%22&amp;amp;time=%2200:48%22&amp;amp;moment=%22DEPARTURE%22&amp;amp;selected_trip=2&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Connection Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will take a train back at 17:17 or 18:17 arriving in Zurich at 18:55 or 19:55, respectively, depending on the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tickets&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tickets:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note that the tickets for trains etc. are not going to be organized collectively. We are going to travel a lot, so it pays off to buy a day pass (Tageskarte). It allows for flexibility and is valid for boats, as well. There is either the Spartageskarte possibly combined with Halbtax, which has to be purchased in advance and whose price grows with time, or the Friends-Tageskarte Jugend, which has a fixed price of 80 Fr. and can be used by up to 4 persons under the age of 25 (max 24,99), i.e. if 4 people share one ticket, each one has to pay 20 Fr. only. You can use the WhatsApp group (see below) to arrange the ticket with others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;communication&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a WhatsApp group for any news &amp;amp; meeting arrangements: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://chat.whatsapp.com/FOfDPDLK9nFCJh96XDCgTd?mode=ems_copy_t&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Link to join WhatsApp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>General Assembly</title>
        <link>https://cssz.ch/events/general-assembly-hs25/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cssz.ch/events/general-assembly-hs25/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://cssz.ch/images/events/2023-05-25-general-meeting/meeting2.jpg" alt="Featured image of post General Assembly" /&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusions-from-the-general-meeting&#34;&gt;Conclusions from the General Meeting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to everyone who joined the General Assembly. We are very happy so many of you help us run CSSZ.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The General Assembly voted and passed the following agenda points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elect Klára Kolářová as the president of CSSZ for the next term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Elect Radim Urban, Max Kellenberger, Aleš Kubíček and Zdeněk Šnajdr as Board members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;initial-invitation&#34;&gt;Initial Invitation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear CSSZ members,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On September 26th we will host a General Assembly (GA). We will look back at our activities of the last year, discuss the direction the society should take and elect a new board. In addition, we will vote on the new version of the statutes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Summary of last academic year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Election of CSSZ Board&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vote on the new statutes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you have a proposal you would like to discuss, please submit it here: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://forms.gle/zst4GqfJdaWLLW3X7&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://forms.gle/zst4GqfJdaWLLW3X7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Board of Czech and Slovak Students in Zurich&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>VSUZH Activity Fair HS25</title>
        <link>https://cssz.ch/events/uzh-activity-fair-hs25/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cssz.ch/events/uzh-activity-fair-hs25/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://cssz.ch/images/events/2024-09-25-uzh-activity-fair/activity_fair.jpg" alt="Featured image of post VSUZH Activity Fair HS25" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Come and support CSSZ at the VSUZH Activity Fair!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the right place to learn and ask in person who we are, what we do, how to join us and how to help our efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;vsuzh-activity-fair&#34;&gt;VSUZH Activity Fair&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you have a passion and want to share it with other students? Looking for experiences that complement the knowledge you gained during your studies? The VSUZH Activity Fair is THE fair for student engagement at the University of Zurich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here you can meet the people behind the student organisations and initiatives that are active at the University. Immerse yourself in the diversity of student life and find out which organization suits you best!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next VSUZH Activity Fair will take place on &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, 24 September 2025&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;09:30&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;15:30&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Lichthof UZH Center&lt;/strong&gt; and on &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, 25 September&lt;/strong&gt; from &lt;strong&gt;09:30&lt;/strong&gt; to &lt;strong&gt;15:30&lt;/strong&gt; at &lt;strong&gt;Lichthof Irchel&lt;/strong&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Semester Welcome Event (Autumn 2025)</title>
        <link>https://cssz.ch/events/welcome-event-autumn25/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://cssz.ch/events/welcome-event-autumn25/</guid>
        <description>&lt;img src="https://cssz.ch/images/events/2024-09-27-welcome-event-autumn24/zh_from_bQm.jpeg" alt="Featured image of post Semester Welcome Event (Autumn 2025)" /&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us for a lively kick-off to the Autumn semester 2025 at the bQm bar 🍻, where the Czech and Slovak Students in Zurich will meet up for a beer⭐. This is a great opportunity for both new and existing students to meet🤝. We look forward to seeing you there! 🎉&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
